Giuseppe Di Bella

OBJECTIVE

JAVA PROGRAMMER I have been working as a Java Developer for more than 15 years now, gaining a significant experience in developing complex applications. I have worked both in medium size and large companies, in different sectors such as e-commerce, finance, bank, public administration, gaming. From the start of my career in IT I have been constantly building upon my existing knowledge of multi-tier applications. I have been regularly working with J2EE frameworks such as Strut2, Spring, Hibernate, JPA reaching a high level of expertise. In the last six months I.v been using mainly groovy and scala. I have an excellent knowledge of SQL language. I am fully conversant with Oracle DB, including PL/SQL, Mysql,Postgres,Bigquery and MSSQL. Lately I moved to MongoDb, writing complex queries for "Big Data" database. I have a strong knowledge of Continuous Integration using Jenkins with Maven and Shell Remote commands. I have also a good knowledge of heroku environments and snap-ci pipelines. In addition to a strong technical knowledge I have also acquired a good experience as a team leader. I have been using Agile methodologies such as Scrum and I work using XP, BDD and TDD methodologies. I am really passionate about technologies. I am always eager to learn new skills.

EDUCATION

Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) 6

April 2010

Degree in Geology Universita Statale di Pavia, Italy

March 1995

Diploma di Maturita Scientifica Liceo Scientifico G. Seguenza, Messina, Italy

June 1989

SKILLS/KNOWLEDGES

- Operative Systems. DOS, Windows 95/98/2000/NT/Vista/Win7-11, MacOs, Unix, Linux (Slackware, Ubuntu, Debian,RedHat)
- Languages. Java, Groovy, Pl/Sql, MsSql, JavaScript, Shell Unix (bash)
- Technical DBC/DC .Bigquery , Oracle, Mysql, Postgres, SQL Server, Apache, Gatling, Tomcat, Wild-Fly AS, Bea WebLogic, Maven, SVN, Git, Ant, Hibernate, JMS, SmartFoxServer2, MongoDb, Multi-Threading, Jenkins, Spring, EJB3, JPA, Jersey, Heroku, AWS Modelling language. UML
- PC applications. Eclipse, Excel, Word, Access, Outlook, Visual Studio,
- IDE. Intellij IDEA, Eclipse, NetBeans, Jedit
- Methodologies . XP, TDD, Scrum, BDD, CD/CI

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pottermore
Full Stack Java Developer Devops

 $December\ 2015-Present$

• Pottermore is the portal to the wizarding world of J.K, Rowling the Harry Potter books writer. The website is the main source of information about the news related to the Harry Potter worlds/works. As a Full Stack Java developer I create with the internal team new features for the website and the integration with the third part providers as Shopify and Sendgrid. The language is mainly Groovy for

the backend and Angular for the frontend. We also use Gatling (Based on Scala) for the performance tests. We also integrate our system with Google Cloud (especially Bigquery) for internal data analysis. The role also includes a support rota for the website using Opsgenie tools and a series of monitoring alerts. The team uses a scrum/kanban methodology, Jira and an agile approach including TDD, XP ans CI/CD. Responsabilities:

- Writing new backend services providing integration with third part providers (Shopify, Stormpath, Google Cloud)
- Maintenance and refactoring of services and design of integration and end 2 end tests
- Maintenance and creation of monitoring services, integrating bespoke alerting services with Opsgenie and Slack
- Creation and maintence of new pipelines for CI/CD
- Creation and maintenance of data workflows using Google Cloud and Bigquery for accountancy and analytic purposes

Amelco

June 2015 – December 2015

Senior Java Developer

• Amelco is a Service Provider Company for the betting Industry providing data integration for some of the main companies of the sector in the UK. I am working on the integration of Virtual Betting Games using a Micro Services approach with Spring Boot. The application uses the Spring Batch framework to convert data from the external system to the internal platform. I am also part of a team for the support and the bug fixing of one of the bespoke applications. The team uses a scrum methodology, Jira and an agile approach including TDD and BDD.

PlayLine Studios

May 2012 – June 2015

Analyst Programmer on Java platform

- Playline Studios is a startup company in the gambling sector. I have written two different games (slot machines) creating the server side of multiplayer games online. The games use a socket server (SmartServerFox2) and they are multithreaded applications. A Spring component is used to save data in the database. The applications can use different data layers, as Mysql and MongoDb. The projects are developed using Maven and Jenkins for Continuous Integration. The second game uses also a basic rule engine to compensate results. The team was using a scrum methodology with daily stand up meeting, and strongly focused on TDD.
- I have also created java clients for the massive load tests and to verify the RTP results of the slots.
- Continous Integration Manager using Jenkins.

Energee3 Srl, Turin, Italy

Apr 2011 - March 2012

Team Leader and Analyst Programmer on Java platform

• ACCRA Accreditamento Ambientale.

The scope of this application is to build a centralised authentication for environmental web applications of the Piedmont Region in Italy. The web application is built with Ejb3, Jpa, Struts2, Spring, Hibernate and Jquery. I was technical leader and developer on all stacks of the application.

- Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
- Writing database queries for complex searches
- Coding Ejb Services and related tests
- Writing Web Services and related tests
- Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)
- SKVIA Procedure Via.

The scope of this application is to provide information about the environmental impact of industrial activities and large public works. I was the technical leader and developer of the project. The application is built with Ejb3, Jpa, Struts2, Hibernate, Spring and Jquery and provides Soap Web Services for other applications of the public administration network.

- Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
- Coding Ejb Services and related tests
- Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)

Alten Italia Dec 2009 – Mar 2011

Team Leader and Analyst Programmer on Java platform

• Sipra Project Management.

Application for managing the account rendering of Sipras internal projects. Technologies used: framework Struts, Spring on application server Tomcat and database Oracle using stored procedure PL/SQL. Front-end technologies: Jquery.

- Collecting requirements for the product and Writing Documents of Analysis
- Creating Database Structure and Store Procedure (PL/SQL) Coding Web Services and related tests
- Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)
- Television Advertising System.

B2B E-commerce application used by the Italian television company RAI for sending advertising spots. Application use a JMS system to send alerts to cinemas about adverts to be transmitted before projections. Technological stack: JMS, Spring, Struts2, Oracle DB.

- Creating Rest Web Services
- Creating Database Structure and Queries
- Creating Client Application Reading the Messages coming from the Central System
- Web Console to manage the system configuration
- Maintenance Clipper applications.

Correptive and Adaptive Software maintenance in Public Administration context for GTT Group, Torino.

Csi Piemonte (on behalf of Pro Logic)

Aug 2008 Dec 2009

Team Leader and Analyst Programmer on Java platform

• Project Sipred.

Application for managing of Administrative Procedures for Turin council (maintenance and house building permits). Application developed using J2EE tecnology on the server side; Ejb, Spring e Soap Web Services on Application Server Bea Weblogic and database Oracle. IOC (Spring) and Struts2 framework used on the web side.

- Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
- Writing database queries for complex searches Coding Ejb Services and related tests
- Writing Soap Web Services and related tests
- Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)
- Project Testing Index-Acta.

Design and development of a suite of automated tests to use on the documental administration project of Csi Piemonte. Development of an engine for testing with data charged from a database (MySql) for the automatization of suite of test Junit. Employment of Open Source tools: Selenium with Xpath for web pages testing, SoapUi for the automation of web services testing.

- Team Leader
- Creation of a database to save test data and results
- Writing an engine to automate test execution extracting data from database
- Team leader for a group of testers
- Writing automatic test suite using the result of selenium records
- Creation of test suite for SoapUi

Scai Spa Jan 2008 - Jun 2008

Team Leader and Analyst Programmer on Java platform

• Project Appj.

Application for the Supply Chain Management of Comune di Torino. The application was developed with J2EE technology on the server side, employing Ejb on Application Server Bea Weblogic and database Oracle. On the client side we employed the libraries of the TikeSwing framework (MVC system for Swing).

- Team Leader and main point of contact for customers
- Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
- Writing database queries for complex searches
- Coding Client using TikeSwing

Csp Spa (on behalf of Ulixe)

Jan 2007 Dec 2007

Intranet Analyst Programmer on Java platform

• Project Tributi-Tarsu-Ici.

Corrective and Adaptive Software maintenance of the applications developed by Csp for Csi Piemonte. The application was developed with J2EE technology on server WebLogic BEA server and employed the Struts framework for the front-end, Spring and EJB 2.0 technology for the Business Logic and DAO pattern for data management on Oracle database.

- Java Developer

Csi Piemonte (on behalf of SCAI)

Oct 2004 Dec 2006

Intranet Web Analyst Programmer on Java platform

- Project Anagrafica Interlocutori. The projects goal was the maintenance of a register of people and legal entities that interact with Csi Piemonte. The aim was to build a database for sending free gifts and publications. The application was developed with J2EE technology and Oracle database, employing the Struts framework and EJB for the business side.
 - Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
 - Writing database queries for complex searches
 - Coding Ejb Services and related tests
 - Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)
- Project Geofre Gestione offerte regione.

The projects goal was the creation of CSI proposals for the Regione Piemonte and their account rendering. The application was developed with Java technology employing Apache Tomcat as application server and Oracle as database. The application was built according to J2EE standards and could be utilized also with proprietary servlet container (Bea WebLogic). The communication with the database was realized exclusively through PL/SQL procedures and a Java bean layer that allows the possible shift to an EJB based platform. The interface part employed the velocity templates and style sheets CSS2.

- Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
- Writing database queries for complex searches
- Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)

Istituto Bancario Sanpaolo IMI (on behalf of Shift srl)

Oct 2001 Jul 2004

Intranet Web Analyst Programmer on Java platform

• Project Infrastruttura Documentale.

The projects goal was the Project Documentation management of the Istituto Bancario Sanpaolo. The web application was developed with Java technology employing Oracle Content Management SDK and OC4J as application server.

• Project Monografie.

Monografie is a web application for the "distribution and management of monographs". With this application it was possible to manage the monographs, by creating catalogues, managing inventory and creating distribution plans to allocate the above items to each branch of the bank. The distribution can take place periodically following preplanned criteria (e.g. end of year free gifts) or upon request from the branch which requires the items. The web application was developed with Java technology employing Bea WebLogic as application server and Oracle database.

- Verifing Database Structure and changing it as necessary
- Writing database queries for complex searches
- Developing across all layers of a JEE application (front-end, web tier, services tier)

INTERESTS

From a very young age I have been an enthusiastic choir member, starting in the church choir of my home town, followed by the choirs of my schools and university. I was often given solo parts. I am also an amateur piano player. I am a keen and much appreciated cook.